hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation playlist so
continuing with our topic on test
automation obstacles let's look at our
next obstacle which is called the
addition now this is a pretty simple
obstacle where we need to to uh add two
numbers and then provide the sum of the
number here the only challenge here is
these two numbers are not static they
are two randomly generated numbers okay
so if now I refresh this particular page
you will see that this numbers change
okay so that's the only difficulty here
so you need to um add these two numbers
which are randomly generated and change
every time and then you need to uh
get the sum and write it here okay so
for example if this is
143 and then uh you will see that the
obstacle is completed okay so pretty
simple if you know how to do this so
let's see uh in tosa how we can uh
achieve this particular obstacle
right so coming back here uh first we
need to scan this particular application
okay so here I'm going to scan the
application and then um we will look out
for the numbers so here are the numbers
you can see and then uh we have also the
result right which is a text box so now
if you look at these two numbers we
don't actually need the numbers we need
the elements and then using the inner
text we can get the actual value right
so what I'm going to do here is I'm
going to change the names here I'm going
to call this num one and num two
right and then um I'm going to see this
obstacle okay so I'm going to copy this
number and I'm going to rename this
module okay and then I'm going to save
this okay so our module is ready now uh
this is the module
and you can see num one num two and the
result right so now uh let's go to our
test cases and then under obstacles we
are going to create a new test case
here okay and then uh we are also going
to drag the module into this test case
right now coming to this particular test
case uh now we have got the number one
right but it is randomly generated so we
cannot just uh scan that particular
element and then use the value there
right so we need to basically store this
into a variable so that whatever uh
number is um being displayed on the page
it can capture that and save it
somewhere right so the best possible
option is to buffer that particular
number
right so I'm going to change uh the
action mode to buffer here and then uh
we are going to grab the inner text of
this particular number right and uh we
are going to save it into a buffer
right uh and the same we are going to do
for the next number we are going to use
buffer here and we are going to get the
inner text and save it into another
buffer right so this this way uh we can
grab the numbers um even if those are
randomly generated we will get the
numbers which are currently present on
the page right so once we have got the
numbers and we have stored them into
buffers now we need to add those two
numbers right now I cannot directly go
ahead and add uh two buffers like bore
num 1 plus bore num2 it will give you no
result
right uh because uh tosa needs a
function through which it can perform
the mathematical calculations and that
function is called the math function
okay so using this math
expression uh you can perform any kind
of mathematical calculations whether it
is addition subtraction multiplication
division or any other mathematical
calculation you want to do you have to
use the math expression right so uh here
in the result what we are going to do we
are going going to use the math
expression as I said inside this we need
to provide the operant and the operator
right so here the operant are the
buffers so I'm going to use buffer here
so I'm going to build this particular
expression
here okay and then I'm going to use the
operator here plus as the operator we
want to add the two numbers right so
here again the next buffer
and I'm going to build this
so and num two and then um I'm going to
close this
okay so this is how the expression looks
like okay so we have used the math
expression inside that we have our
operant and the operator uh which is
nothing but the addition operator
right so now uh let's go ahead and
execute this and let's see whether it is
able to add the two numbers and enter it
into the text box or
not okay so here uh you can see that uh
it entered uh the number or sum of the
two numbers which is correct right but
even though it entered correctly the sum
you can see the obstacle was not
completed I mean we did not get the
message that it was completed
and the reason for that is uh we just
inputed the number right but here uh
this particular application what it is
expecting that you are typing the number
like a normal user right so for that uh
we need to change how we input the
numbers into the text box okay so rather
than just inputting them what we will do
uh we will enter the keys one by one
okay and and for
that we are going to use something
called the send Keys expression right so
using the send Keys expression we can
send the keys one by one and in that way
it will emulate a user typing the number
into the text box okay so let's see if
that makes a difference so I'm just
going to put the same expression inside
the send Keys now okay so this is how
the expression will look like so let's
go ahead and execute this and see
whether it makes any difference or not
right so I'm going to refresh this page
so that we get some new numbers here and
then uh we are going to execute that uh
from the test case right so let's go
ahead and execute that before that I
will change the work state to complet it
and then I'll execute
this and this time around you will see
that uh the message uh will appear and
the difference is pretty clear right so
if you are entering like an user then uh
the application is able to recognize
that okay the numbers have been entered
but if you just use the input
function then um it will probably not
work sometimes right even though you
have entered the correct number so
sometimes you need to uh adjust uh the
inputting uh methods in your test cases
but this is how uh you can basically
buffer uh your randomly generated
numbers and then you can use the math
function to uh perform any mathematical
calculation and then you can also use
the send Keys expression to uh enter the
number into the text box
field that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments
if you like this video then please
subscribe to our Channel thanks for
watching and I will see you in the next
video